Hello everyone, welcome to the quick tutorial series of Marlboro's Designer 2025.
In this tutorial, we will introduce you to the view control method in Marlboro's Designer.
First of all, you can go to the main menu, settings, user customization, and find the view control menu.
Select the preview of the operation method according to your needs.
In the user preview download menu, select your usual operation method.
You can choose according to the usual 3D software type or mouse type.
In the view control column, you can also adjust and set certain operation methods separately.
For example, in normal situations, when the mouse wheel rolls backwards, it pulls towards the camera.
But if we move in the direction of the camera,
when the mouse wheel rolls backwards, it pulls towards the camera.
You can save these settings as user customizations and use them later.
You can open the saved settings file in the user customizations.
Or you can directly reset the user customizations and restore the original settings.
In this series of tutorials, we use default settings.
Under default settings, press and hold the middle mouse button and drag the mouse button to parallel.
Whether it is a 3D window or a 2D window, the operation method is the same.
When you move the mouse wheel, you can release the view.
At the same time, press and hold the left mouse button and drag the mouse button to release the view.
The rotation view can only be done in the 3D window.
Press and hold the right mouse button and drag the mouse button to rotate the view.
If we click on a certain object, it will automatically focus on this point.
The rotation view is done in the focus position.
Click on the 3D background again to cancel the focus mode.
Click on the right mouse button and drag the mouse button to the 3D window.
There are also some view options in the 3D window.
First is the correct and wrong view.
You can find and choose them here.
They all have corresponding small keyboard number shortcut keys.
For example, the correct view shortcut key is 2.
Press the number key 2 to go back to the front view.
In addition, you can also choose to change the focal length.
This allows the 3D window to be adjusted so that you can see all visible objects.
This function is very useful for finding hidden objects.
The 2D window can also use the zoom in and out view function to find outside the field of view.
In addition, after selecting the field of view, press the shortcut key F to focus on the selected field of view.
In the 3D window, you can also focus on the selected field of view.
After that, the zoom in and out view is also done by focusing on objects.
This is the tutorial for trying to control.
See you in the next video.